<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>international on </title>
    <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/tags/international/</link>
    <description>Recent content in international on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/tags/international/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JSPS Postdoctoral Fellows</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/postdoc-jsps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/postdoc-jsps/</guid>
      <description>Standard Postdoctoral Fellowships are awarded to overseas PhD researchers for a period of 12-24 months: 1) 362,000 JPY/month (tax free), 2) roundtrip airfare fee coverage, 3) settling-in allowance of up to 200,000 JPY.
 Application Process Joined Application between You (Candidate) &amp;amp; Our Lab/YCU (Host) is required.
 FY-2023 Application (1st Recruitment)  Candidate Required Documents: Standard-FORM2, Letter of Recommendation Document Submission: by August, 2022 (internal deadline) Starting Date: April 1 - September 30, 2023   FY-2023 Application (2nd Recruitment)  Candidate Required Documents: Standard-FORM2, Letter of Recommendation Document Submission: by May, 2023 (internal deadline) Starting Date: September 1 - November 30, 2023   Foreign Nominating Authority (selected countries)  JSPS program application through foreign nominating authorities check details directly with the nominating authority in your country   Recruitment We are looking for Postdocs in : 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral Fellows (other)</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/postdoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/postdoc/</guid>
      <description>Paid Positions There are currently no open Postdoctoral Positions with funding available. Please check again later.
We are open to to potential JSPS applicants (see above) or applicants with own-funding available (see below).
 Self-funded Positions If you have own funding for a postdoc position available, live or want to live in Japan for some time, and your research interests are related to our research, please get in touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Students</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/graduate/</guid>
      <description>Paid Positions There are currently no positions with funding available for Graduate Students.
Self-funded If you have own funding available and are interested in applying to our Medical School as a graduate student, email us</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term Visitors</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/visitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/visitor/</guid>
      <description>JSPS Scholars The Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) carries out programs that provide overseas researchers who have an excellent record of research achievements with an opportunity to conduct collaborative research, discussions, and opinion exchanges with researchers in Japan. These programs are intended to help advance the overseas researchers&amp;rsquo; research activities while promoting science and internationalization in Japan. https://www.jsps.go.jp/english/e-ippan/index.html
Self-funded If you have own funding available, and want to live in Japan for some time while doing collaborative on-site research with, send us an email!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
