<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI in cancer &amp; immunity</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/projects/deeplearn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/projects/deeplearn/</guid>
      <description>Biologically-informed deep neural networks (new) Rapidly growing biological data often requires a development of novel computational algorithms. Ideally, such algorithms would accurately classify biological states, while providing insights into functionality of complex biological systems. Deep learning algorithms are recently emerging as an attractive choice. Despite their high-accuracy in distinguish biological states (ex: pathological images of cancer vs healthy counterparts), deep learning methods, however, tend to use large volumes of raw and often redundant data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromatin structure &amp; lncRNAs myelopoiesis</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/projects/hic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/projects/hic/</guid>
      <description>3D genome structure and lncRNAs in myeloid cells differentiation Classical dendritic cells (cDCs) play very important roles in controlling both innate and adaptive immunity. Under normal conditions, cDCs originate in bone marrow from Common Dendritic Progenitors (CDPs). IRF8 is one of the key transcription factors regulating differentiation of cDCs into cDC1 and cDC2 cell subsets. Surprisingly, cDC2s are also found in lacking CDPs Irf8-deficient mice, suggesting that cDC2s can possibly originate from “hidden” progenitors and/or from existing progenitors through previously unobserved developmental transitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Pathogenesis</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/projects/covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/projects/covid19/</guid>
      <description>Understanding pathology of COVID-19 using NGS and clinical data Since the initial outbreak in December 2019, COVID-19 pandemic resulted in over 500 million infections worldwide while claiming more than 6 million lives (as of April 2022). Despite that a large majority of individuals infected with SARS-CoV-2 (Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus-2) display only mild disease symptoms, it remains to be determined why others become critically, or even terminally, ill.
Extensive research dedicated to understanding COVID-19 disease pathology have established that disease in critical patients is accompanied by:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JSPS Postdoctoral Fellows</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/postdoc-jsps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/postdoc-jsps/</guid>
      <description>Standard Postdoctoral Fellowships are awarded to overseas PhD researchers for a period of 12-24 months: 1) 362,000 JPY/month (tax free), 2) roundtrip airfare fee coverage, 3) settling-in allowance of up to 200,000 JPY.
 Application Process Joined Application between You (Candidate) &amp;amp; Our Lab/YCU (Host) is required.
 FY-2023 Application (1st Recruitment)  Candidate Required Documents: Standard-FORM2, Letter of Recommendation Document Submission: by August, 2022 (internal deadline) Starting Date: April 1 - September 30, 2023   FY-2023 Application (2nd Recruitment)  Candidate Required Documents: Standard-FORM2, Letter of Recommendation Document Submission: by May, 2023 (internal deadline) Starting Date: September 1 - November 30, 2023   Foreign Nominating Authority (selected countries)  JSPS program application through foreign nominating authorities check details directly with the nominating authority in your country   Recruitment We are looking for Postdocs in : 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pancreatic Cancers</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/projects/cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/projects/cancer/</guid>
      <description>Understanding molecular mechanisms of pancreatic cancers Pancreas is the abdominal organ situated behind the lower part of the stomach responsible for releasing digestive enzymes and producing hormones regulating blood sugar levels. As early pancreatic cancers generally show no symptoms, they can grow very large or spread outside the pancreas before being detected. Consequently, pancreatic cancers have a very poor prognosis and are one of the most lethal cancers: 25% of people survive one year while only 5% survive for five years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral Fellows (other)</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/postdoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/postdoc/</guid>
      <description>Paid Positions There are currently no open Postdoctoral Positions with funding available. Please check again later.
We are open to to potential JSPS applicants (see above) or applicants with own-funding available (see below).
 Self-funded Positions If you have own funding for a postdoc position available, live or want to live in Japan for some time, and your research interests are related to our research, please get in touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/intro/</guid>
      <description>Our projects are biologically-driven with the aim to understand biological processes at the molecular &amp;amp; cellular level, so to ultimately help cure diseases and enhance the human life. We use cutting-edge computational algorithms, pipelines and our high-spec computational platform to analyze own and public NGS &amp;amp; clinical data. See also our papers.
Biology  COVID-19 pathology &amp;amp; cancers immune cells differentiation &amp;amp; gene regulation long non-coding RNAs, 3D genome structure, cell–cell communication  Methods &amp;amp; Technologies  statistics, ML, AI/deep-learning (starting) Linux, R, Python, nf-core pipelines RNA-seq, Hi-C, ChIP-seq, ATAC-seq, single cell data  Current Projects  Understanding pathology of COVID-19 using NGS and clinical data 3D genome structure and lncRNAs in myeloid cells differentiation Pancreatic cancer: molecular mechanism of the disease Biologically-informed deep neural networks (new) Other collaborative projects   Want to know more details?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Students</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/graduate/</guid>
      <description>Paid Positions There are currently no positions with funding available for Graduate Students.
Self-funded If you have own funding available and are interested in applying to our Medical School as a graduate student, email us</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Publications</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/papers/</guid>
      <description>All Publications: Tamura Tomohiko All Publications: Ramilowski Jordan
 2020 - now  A RUNX–CBFβ-driven enhancer directs the Irf8 dose-dependent lineage choice between DCs and monocytes. Nat Immunol 22(3), 301-311, 2021 Genetic and chemical inhibition of IRF5 suppresses pre-existing mouse lupus-like disease.
Nat Commun 12(1), 4379, 2021 FANTOM enters 20th year: expansion of transcriptomic atlases and functional annotation of non-coding RNAs. Nuc Acid Res 49 (D1), D892-D898, 2021 Combined inhibition of XIAP and BCL2 drives maximal therapeutic efficacy in genetically diverse aggressive acute myeloid leukemia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term Visitors</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/visitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/visitor/</guid>
      <description>JSPS Scholars The Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) carries out programs that provide overseas researchers who have an excellent record of research achievements with an opportunity to conduct collaborative research, discussions, and opinion exchanges with researchers in Japan. These programs are intended to help advance the overseas researchers&amp;rsquo; research activities while promoting science and internationalization in Japan. https://www.jsps.go.jp/english/e-ippan/index.html
Self-funded If you have own funding available, and want to live in Japan for some time while doing collaborative on-site research with, send us an email!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staff Positions</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/staff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/recruitment/staff/</guid>
      <description>There are currently no Staff Positions available in our lab. Please check again later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/news/</guid>
      <description>We are looking for JSPS Postdoc Applicants to join our lab! 2022   Apr 01, 2022: Jordan 5th Strategic Research Promotion Project Grant (2021-2023) was renewed this internal grant helps to promote YCU researchers in pursuing their career goals by giving them independent funding. We very much appreciate a continues support of the YCU President&amp;rsquo;s Office!
Congratulations on your positive grant evaluation Jordan-sensei!
  Feb 25, 2022: Tomohiko receives YCU President Award</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BI Lab</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/intro/</guid>
      <description>Yokohama City University (YCU) is a prominent and dynamically growing Education &amp;amp; Research Institution in Japan. In 2006, Advanced Medical Research Center (AMRC/SENTANKEN) was formed to help YCU&amp;rsquo;s mission of enhancing and promoting medically-relevant research through various industry and academic collaborations.
 Bioinformatics Laboratory (BI Lab) was first formed as a lab within AMRC (2009) and it has existed in its current form since August 2020. Our main mission is to conduct biologically-relevant research to enhance clinical and medical discoveries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/equipment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/research/equipment/</guid>
      <description>We use programming languages (R, Python, shell), computational algorithms and nf-core pipelines to analyze a variety of NGS (RNA-seq, Hi-C, ChIP-seq/CUTnTag/CutnRUN, ATAC-seq, single-cell data, etc.) and clinical data. High-end Computational &amp;amp; LTO Tape System servers are installed onsite to efficiently analyze and store our data. Our sequencing platform includes 10x Chromium Controler and NextSeq 500 sequencer.
Nabe Takeru two large-memory computational servers: AMD EPYC 7742 2TB RAM/128 CPU threads (top) &amp;amp; Intel E7-8867v4 2TB RAM/72 CPU threads (bottom).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FY-2022 Bioinformatics Courses (online)</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/teaching/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/teaching/courses/</guid>
      <description>01. Practical Bioinformatics  8 Lectures: English Date: 16th May - 03rd October, 2022 Day/Time: Monday @17:30-19:30 JST Registration: until 21-Apr-2022 YCU Graduate Students elective subject (選択講義)   02. Current Trends in Bioinformatics  8 Lectures: Japanese/English Date: 17th October - 05th December, 2022 Day/Time: Monday @16:10-17:40 JST Registration: not yet open YCU Graduate Students elective subject (選択講義)   03. Advanced Practical Bioinformatics Topic: Single-cell Data Analysis
 4 Lectures: English Date: January-February, 2023 (putative) Day/Time: Monday @17:30-19:30 JST (putative) Registration: not yet open   Interested in joining our BI online courses, but NOT a YCU Student/Faculty/Collaborator, please email us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/members/</guid>
      <description>Faculty  Tomohiko TAMURA, Lab Head &amp;amp; Immunology Professor Jordan RAMILOWSKI, Bioinformatics Associate Professor  Staff  Irie YASUKAWA, Lab Support  Visiting Researchers  Jun NAKABAYASHI, Visiting Professor (Professor, Tokyo Medical and Dental University)  Previous Members  Karen SATO, Summer Intern (June – August, 2021) Fumitaka UEMATSU, Undergraduate Researcher (April 2021 – March 2022) Jun NAKABAYASHI, Associate Professor (2012 – 2020) Naoki OSATO, Associate Professor (2009 – 2012)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/teaching/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~bioinfo/teaching/intro/</guid>
      <description>All our courses are online and are open to YCU Students (free), Faculty Members, and to YCU Collaborators.
Join our FY-2022 Courses!
 *01. Practical Bioinformatics (English) this course helps our medical students and experimental researchers to learn basic theoretical and practical aspects of Next Generation Sequencing (NGS) Data Analysis. Students learn to write, debug and execute simple and reproducible R codes using RStudio and perform most common NGS data functional analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
